<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Codenotebook on ...Down the Rabbit Hole...</title>
    <link>/tags/codenotebook/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Codenotebook on ...Down the Rabbit Hole...</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/codenotebook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux find examples</title>
      <link>/2014/06/10/linux-find/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/06/10/linux-find/</guid>
      <description>I just wanted to record a few short find commands that are very fast and useful.
To find all the files modified on a specific date, in the case below the 13th May 2014:
$ find . -type f -name &amp;quot;*&amp;quot; -newermt 2014-05-13 ! -newermt 2014-05-14 ./Phd/NI_genetic_data/SNPloci_update_May-2013/bed/male_Y_SNPS.hh ./Phd/NI_genetic_data/SNPloci_update_May-2013/bed/male_Y_SNPS.log ./Phd/NI_genetic_data/SNPloci_update_May-2013/bed/male_Y_SNPS.map ./Phd/NI_genetic_data/SNPloci_update_May-2013/bed/male_Y_SNPS.nof ./Phd/NI_genetic_data/SNPloci_update_May-2013/bed/male_Y_SNPS.ped ./Phd/NI_genetic_data/SNPloci_update_May-2013/bed/plink.hh ./Phd/NI_genetic_data/SNPloci_update_May-2013/bed/plink.log ./Phd/NI_genetic_data/SNPloci_update_May-2013/bed/plink.nof ./Presentations/Genemappers_2014/conference_notes/example_expression_variance.png ./Presentations/Genemappers_2014/conference_notes/notes_20140513.txt  You can also append ls to the above to get more detailed information about the files:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power calculations in R</title>
      <link>/2014/05/01/r-powercalcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/05/01/r-powercalcs/</guid>
      <description>Power calculations are an essential element of good experimental design. They can inform on appropriate sample sizes to detect effects of a given size with varying degrees of confidence, or even provide information on the degree of confidence one will have within the confines of a small sample size and the maximum effect sizes one would expect to detect.
It may just be me, but there always seems to be something mystically ‘scary’ about power calculations, peoples perception of them, and how to go about them (until recently I’m not ashamed to have included myself in all 3!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a QuasR target file using the terminal</title>
      <link>/2014/04/28/terminal-formatting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/04/28/terminal-formatting/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just recieved some sequencing data from a couple of Illumina HiSeq lanes and need to run some QC and initial analyses for the miR RNA-seq experiment.
As this my introduction into RNA-seq I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a little reading and came across a very nice overview of using R/Bioconductor for RNA-seq analysis: Thomas Girke - Analysis of RNA-Seq Data with R/Bioconductor
I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to give QuasR a go, I&amp;rsquo;ll report back either here or on the blog with progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Linux sort variants</title>
      <link>/2014/04/10/linux-sort/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2014 10:55:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/04/10/linux-sort/</guid>
      <description>I just wanted a quick reference to look back on.
You have a list of chromosomes in a random order:
$ cat chr.list chr3 chr6 chr2 chr11 chr5 chr7 chr9 chr10 chr1 chr4 chr8 chr12 chr20 chr22  Default sort:
$ cat chr.list | sort chr1 chr10 chr11 chr12 chr2 chr20 chr22 chr3 chr4 chr5 chr6 chr7 chr8 chr9  Sort with &amp;ndash;version-sort:
$ cat chr.list | sort --version-sort chr1 chr2 chr3 chr4 chr5 chr6 chr7 chr8 chr9 chr10 chr11 chr12 chr20 chr22  Another way to get the same as above:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>