<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>...Down the Rabbit Hole...</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ...Down the Rabbit Hole...</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 10:00:33 +1200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop - Methlyation and EWAS</title>
      <link>/2017/05/31/ewas-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 10:00:33 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/31/ewas-workshop/</guid>
      <description>This is a basic EWAS tutorial, introducing concepts for analysing methylation data.
There is a webpage version of the tutorial located here. You can load this and follow along as you run through this on your computer, if you wish to copy paste code please feel free to do so.
Data The workshop uses public Illumina 450K data from several studies (GSE40279, GSE48472, GSE41114, GSE42700, GSE46573, GSE48472, GSE50586). It is currently designed to investigate the methylation differences between blood (whole blood) and buccal (cheek swabs) tissues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations &amp; Posters</title>
      <link>/presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 10:16:33 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/presentations/</guid>
      <description>Presentations 2019 Benton MC. The Humble Guinea Pig: Cute, Furry and Deserving of a Better Genome Assembly? Queenstown Research Week, Queenstown, NZ, August 6th 2019. [HTML Presentation] Benton MC. Genomics and Data Science at ESR ...something a little different... University of Otago, Dunedin, NZ, August 20th 2019. [HTML Presentation] Benton MC. A Customisable Analysis Pipeline for the Identification of Clinically Relevant Genetic Variants in Next Generation Sequencing Data Human Genetics Society of Australasia, Wellington, NZ, August 3rd-6th 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 17:32:32 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>(Where able I have provided a link to the full article.) 2019  Kennedy DW, Mengersen K, Benton MC, Lea RL and White NM. 2019 Bayesian inference for methylation-based cell-type composition estimation. BMC Bioinformatics (under submission)  Benton MC, Black MA, Clapham J, Stubbs RS, and Macartney-Coxson D. 2019 Transcriptional and DNA methylome analysis of the jejunum in individuals with and without type-two diabetes highlights genes involved in glucose homeostasis and pancreatic function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Norfolk Island Whole Genome Sequencing Project</title>
      <link>/2017-05-23-ni-wgs-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 10:22:30 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017-05-23-ni-wgs-project/</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip;updates to come&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>...Down the Rabbit Hole...</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a computational geneticist interested in all facets of biology and technology. I am currently working at ESR (Institute of Environmental Science and Research) as a Senior Scientist in Bioinformatics and Data Science.
In 2014 I completed my PhD exploring the underlying genetic susceptibility to obesity and metabolic disorders in the Norfolk Island population isolate. My main areas of interest are Bioinformatics and Computational Genomics.
My current work involves the creation of methods to deal with, and analyse, large genomic data sets, including the incorporation of multiple layers of both phenotypic and genomic data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>That&#39;s my root partition you&#39;re hogging!</title>
      <link>/2015/10/21/r-libraries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/10/21/r-libraries/</guid>
      <description>I recently noticed that my / (root) partition was not so slowly running out of space. This was somewhat alarming as I&amp;rsquo;d given it a generous 23Gb of SSD space which is surely overkill for a Debian install&amp;hellip;
Well it turns out that the culprit was R, more specifically the default site-library located in /usr/local/lib/R/site-library:
$ sudo du -h /usr/local/lib/R/site-library 6.0G	/usr/local/lib/R/site-library/  That&amp;rsquo;s 6Gb of R packages dominating my root directory, thanks Bioconductor!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Genomewide Association Studies</title>
      <link>/2015/06/26/gwas-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 10:15:30 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/06/26/gwas-workshop/</guid>
      <description>In this workshop we will explore the basics of performing Genomewide Association Studies (GWAS) using a combination of the software plink (http://pngu.mgh.harvard.edu/~purcell/plink/) and R (http://www.r-project.org/).
At a later stage (a separate workshop) we will also introduce the GenABEL package which offers additional functionality of genomic association analyses in R.
This workshop is written to be accessible to a range of people, from those that have never performed any command-line work, to those that just want a refresher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A nice how-to series for writing scientific communications</title>
      <link>/2014/10/02/scientific-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/10/02/scientific-communication/</guid>
      <description>How-to&amp;rsquo;s of writing scientific communications Very brief post to remind me to go back and read these in more detail!
I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been asked to submit a couple of articles to Nature. One thing that seems to be an absolute must for even getting a look in to a journal such as this is a well written cover letter. Hence I went on the hunt for any tips/tricks/suggestions that were scattered around the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Inkscape Scientific Poster Design Workshop</title>
      <link>/2014/09/11/poster-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 09:13:30 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/09/11/poster-workshop/</guid>
      <description>This is a very brief initial workshop designed to introduce Inkscape. The main goal here is to get a general overview of how to create a poster layout with Inkscape, get familiar with the software, and understand a little about putting a scientific poster together.
A pdf version of this workshop can be downloaded here.
I&amp;rsquo;m aiming to have an online version of this workshop avaiable in the not too distant future, watch this space!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources for getting started in a world of open-source software</title>
      <link>/2014/07/23/software-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 11:05:30 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/07/23/software-resources/</guid>
      <description>This is a list of resources that I&amp;rsquo;ve found useful to combine as a handout for students (from teaching a range of different courses).
You can download the list in pdf form here if you like printing documents to read later.
I&amp;rsquo;m currently in the process of adding this material as an online post, so check back often!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Considering Poster Design and Presentation</title>
      <link>/2014/07/22/poster-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 13:45:30 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/07/22/poster-design/</guid>
      <description>This is just a small comment piece I put together on [my] ideas behind the philosophy of design and scientific posters. It also includes quite a few links to sites and blogs that I have found useful and have got a lot of inspiration from.
You can download these in pdf form here if you like printing documents to read later.
I&amp;rsquo;m currently in the process of adding this material as an online post, so check back often!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux find examples</title>
      <link>/2014/06/10/linux-find/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/06/10/linux-find/</guid>
      <description>I just wanted to record a few short find commands that are very fast and useful.
To find all the files modified on a specific date, in the case below the 13th May 2014:
$ find . -type f -name &amp;quot;*&amp;quot; -newermt 2014-05-13 ! -newermt 2014-05-14 ./Phd/NI_genetic_data/SNPloci_update_May-2013/bed/male_Y_SNPS.hh ./Phd/NI_genetic_data/SNPloci_update_May-2013/bed/male_Y_SNPS.log ./Phd/NI_genetic_data/SNPloci_update_May-2013/bed/male_Y_SNPS.map ./Phd/NI_genetic_data/SNPloci_update_May-2013/bed/male_Y_SNPS.nof ./Phd/NI_genetic_data/SNPloci_update_May-2013/bed/male_Y_SNPS.ped ./Phd/NI_genetic_data/SNPloci_update_May-2013/bed/plink.hh ./Phd/NI_genetic_data/SNPloci_update_May-2013/bed/plink.log ./Phd/NI_genetic_data/SNPloci_update_May-2013/bed/plink.nof ./Presentations/Genemappers_2014/conference_notes/example_expression_variance.png ./Presentations/Genemappers_2014/conference_notes/notes_20140513.txt  You can also append ls to the above to get more detailed information about the files:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power calculations in R</title>
      <link>/2014/05/01/r-powercalcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/05/01/r-powercalcs/</guid>
      <description>Power calculations are an essential element of good experimental design. They can inform on appropriate sample sizes to detect effects of a given size with varying degrees of confidence, or even provide information on the degree of confidence one will have within the confines of a small sample size and the maximum effect sizes one would expect to detect.
It may just be me, but there always seems to be something mystically ‘scary’ about power calculations, peoples perception of them, and how to go about them (until recently I’m not ashamed to have included myself in all 3!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a QuasR target file using the terminal</title>
      <link>/2014/04/28/terminal-formatting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/04/28/terminal-formatting/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just recieved some sequencing data from a couple of Illumina HiSeq lanes and need to run some QC and initial analyses for the miR RNA-seq experiment.
As this my introduction into RNA-seq I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a little reading and came across a very nice overview of using R/Bioconductor for RNA-seq analysis: Thomas Girke - Analysis of RNA-Seq Data with R/Bioconductor
I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to give QuasR a go, I&amp;rsquo;ll report back either here or on the blog with progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Linux sort variants</title>
      <link>/2014/04/10/linux-sort/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2014 10:55:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/04/10/linux-sort/</guid>
      <description>I just wanted a quick reference to look back on.
You have a list of chromosomes in a random order:
$ cat chr.list chr3 chr6 chr2 chr11 chr5 chr7 chr9 chr10 chr1 chr4 chr8 chr12 chr20 chr22  Default sort:
$ cat chr.list | sort chr1 chr10 chr11 chr12 chr2 chr20 chr22 chr3 chr4 chr5 chr6 chr7 chr8 chr9  Sort with &amp;ndash;version-sort:
$ cat chr.list | sort --version-sort chr1 chr2 chr3 chr4 chr5 chr6 chr7 chr8 chr9 chr10 chr11 chr12 chr20 chr22  Another way to get the same as above:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to R and RStudio</title>
      <link>/2013/07/01/r-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 12:43:30 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/07/01/r-workshop/</guid>
      <description>This is a workshop I put together during my PhD in attempt to help others wanting to learn and ultise the power of R in their studies/work.
In the mean time, a pdf version of this workshop can be downloaded here.
Note: This workshop was last updated on the 5th October 2012, and I have good intentions of updating it - therefore it is a work in progress and may contain some dead links and outdated software versions, however the core concepts are still accurate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Norfolk Island Health Study</title>
      <link>/2010-05-04-nihs-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010-05-04-nihs-project/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been lucky enough to work with the people of Norfolk Island since 2010 during my PhD through to present with aspects of my postdoc research.
 Norfolk Island is a remote island in the Pacific that has a unique and well-documented history and genealogy that makes its population an ideal candidate for genetic research. The finding of a population as genetically unique and geographically isolated as Norfolk Island is very rare and is therefore of vital importance in the field of human genetic research.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>